when the flesh is exposed the devil sees
you because the devil is attracted to
flesh the Bible says here you are the
light of the world a city that is set on
a hill cannot be hid neither do men
light a candle and put it under a bushel
but on a candlestick that it may give
light onto all that are in the house let
your light so shine before men that they
may see your good works and glorify your
father which is in heaven the Bible
tells us that as a church we are not to
be hid our church is suppose is supposed
to be a light in this world I have a
question for you this morning and the
question is really the title of my
sermon which is an invisible church do
you ever feel like our church is
invisible to our community do you ever
feel that the mission that God has given
us as a church is really not being
accomplished because while we are that
city on the hill this the the the the
city is being hidden have you ever
wished that more people would hear and
understand what it is that you and I
understand you see jesus promised that
the world would take notice of his
church God's church was to be a force
in the world Isaiah 60 verse 1 for
example the Bible says arise shine for
thy light has come and the glory of the
Lord is risen upon thee for behold the
darkness shall cover the earth and gross
darkness the people but the Lord shall
arise upon thee and his glory shall be
seen upon thee and the Gentiles shall
come to thy light and the Kings to the
brightness of thy rising that's a
promise God has given us your church
this church Campbell SDA the seventh-day
Adventist Church in this world was to be
of such force that the world would
recognize God's presence through them
Isaiah 58 another promise Isaiah 58
verse 8 then shall thy light break forth
as the morning
thine health shall spring forth speedily
and thy righteousness shall go before
thee the glory of the Lord shall be thy
reward we were supposed to take the
gospel into all the world according to
Matthew 28 but sometimes it feels like
we are an invisible church a church that
does not get the notice of our
neighborhood a church that does not get
the notice of our community and yet the
question is why why is it that we are an
invisible church and the answer is very
simple
it is because we are visible
let me say that again the reason why we
have an invisible church the reason why
it appears that we are not fulfilling
the mission God has called us the reason
why it appears that our church is
invisible to our large degree is because
we are visible you say pastor what do
you mean please come with me to Genesis
chapter 3 Genesis chapter 3 beginning
with verse 1 the Bible there describes a
story of Adam and Eve and they are
placed in the Garden of Eden and in
Genesis chapter 3 verse 1 that says now
the serpent was more subtle than any
beast of the field which the Lord God
had made and he said unto the woman yay
has God said you shall not eat of every
tree of the garden and the woman said
unto the serpent we may eat of the fruit
of the trees of the garden but of the
fruit of the tree which is in the midst
of the garden God has said you shall not
eat of it neither shall you touch it
lest you die the serpent said unto the
woman you shall not surely die for God
does know in the day you eat thereof
then your eyes shall be opened and ye
shall be as God's knowing good and evil
and when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food and that it was pleasant
to the eyes and a tree to be desired to
make one wise she took of the fruit
thereof and did eat and gave also unto
her husband with her and he did eat and
notice verse 7 the eyes of them both
were once open and they knew that they
were naked and they sewed fig leaves
together and made themselves aprons and
they heard the voice of the Lord God
walking in the garden in the cool of the
day and Adam and his wife what did they
do what did they do when God created
Adam and Eve they were made perfect
we're told that a light covered them and
that light was the glory of God but when
Adam and Eve sinned something happened
can someone tell me what happened when
Adam and Eve sinned
the glory left and when the glory left
please listen carefully when the glory
left which was the glory of God their
flesh became visible their flesh became
visible and when their flesh became
visible it was the sign that God had
left them why are we as a church
struggling with this problem of
invisibility let me suggest to you that
to a great degree it is because we have
become visible the flesh is being
revealed please listen carefully you see
snakes don't really have good eyesight
when the devil sinned he was blinded but
many of us are wondering how is it that
the devil always finds me how is it that
the devil just seems to be on my back so
much and let me answer to you it's
because the devil sends his flesh
I hope you're thinking with me this
morning when the flesh is exposed the
devil sees you because the devil is
attracted to flesh listen listen to what
Jesus says in Matthew chapter 7 verse 16
you shall know them by their fruits do
men gather grapes of thorns or figs of
thistles even so every good tree brings
forth good fruit but a corrupt tree
brings forth evil fruit a good tree
cannot bring forth evil fruit neither
can a corrupt tree bring forth good
fruit every tree that bringeth not forth
good fruit is hewn down and cast into
the fire wherefore by their fruits you
shall want know them so let me ask you
is there good fruit and it's their bad
fruits notice what the Bible says once
again in Romans chapter 7 verse 4
wherefore my brethren you also are
become dead to the law by the body of
Christ that you should be married to
another even to him who is raised from
the dead that you should bring forth
fruit unto God for when we were in the
flesh when we were in the what everyone
the motions of sin which were by the law
did work in our members to bring forth
fruit unto death listen carefully when
we are in the flesh what do we produce
fruit that leads to what that leads to
death so here's my question for you what
are the works of the flesh does the
Bible speak anywhere about the works of
the flesh
yeah Galatians come with me there let's
get it up on the screen Galatians
chapter 5 verse 19 to 21 listen to what
the Bible says here Galatians chapter 5
verse 19 to 21 the Bible says now the
works of the flesh are manifest which
are these adultery fornication
uncleanness lasciviousness idolatry
witchcraft hatred variance emulations
wrath strife seditions heresies verse 21
envyings murders drunkenness revellings
and such like of the which I tell you
before as I've told you in time past
that they which do such things shall not
inherit the kingdom of God let me ask
you a question when you perform the
works of the flesh which are hatred
anger variance envyings what's happening
what's being exposed and what does Satan
see you need to you need to think about
this if Satan is blinded to spiritual
things because the Bible says spiritual
things are spiritually discerned so
Satan is blind to spiritual things he
sees one thing and one thing only and
that is flesh so when you operate in the
flesh when I operate in the flesh what
are you doing
you are attracting the enemy you want to
know how many of you used to play
hide-and-go-seek when you were little
all right
hide-and-go-seek you know you're the
objective of the game is to not be seen
you understand there's a spiritual game
of hide-and-seek and the devil all he
knows is that he's looking for one thing
he's looking for when the flesh
manifests itself
because when the flesh manifests itself
you are in open sight to the enemy and
beloved if you know anything about
combat one of the most important
principles is to not be seen by your
enemy the reason why listen carefully
the reason why our church appears to be
invisible to the community is because we
are visible inside the church Satan sees
us as we dislike one another Satan sees
us as we have attitudes and as we envy
and as we hate and as we do all these
things it's a church manifest of the
flesh and when you are visible in the
church expect to be invisible to the
community because guess what God's if we
cannot love one another in church
if we cannot forbear with one another in
church if we cannot be Christian
brothers and sisters in church we have
no business going out there to the
community and opening our mouth in
anything
God beloved calls us to a higher calling
and beloved listen to me as I look
around at what's happening in our church
around the world I want you do you
realize how much infighting is going on
in our church worldwide over some of the
craziest things you want to know why we
are invisible to the world because we're
a church full of visible people the
flash is being manifested so we have a
problem
Satan sees the flesh he hears it he
smells it he senses it every time you
get angry think about these guys in your
homes
every time you blow up in the church
every time you get angry you are
attracting the enemy of God to you that
sounds to me like a bad horror movie
that's what it sounds like to me like a
bad horror movie you get angry you get
mad you have issues you want to you know
act all in the flesh expect signa be
right there standing next to you because
the flesh is what is visible to Satan so
we have a dilemma but beloved there is a
solution
let me explain come with me to
Revelation chapter 12 verses one through
three Revelation chapter 12 verses one
through three listen to what the Bible
says here beloved Revelation chapter 12
the Bible says there appeared a great
wonder in heaven a woman clothed with
the Sun and a moon under her and the
moon under her feet and upon her head a
crown of twelve stars and she being with
child cried travailing in birth and
pained to be delivered and there
appeared another wonder in heaven and
behold a great red dragon having seven
heads and ten horns and seven Crown's
upon his heads and its tail drew the
third part of his stars of heaven and
did cast them to the earth and I notice
this and the dragon stood before the
woman which was ready to be delivered
for to devour her child as soon as it
was born
and she brought forth a man child who
was to rule all nations with a rod of
iron and her child was caught up unto
God and to his throne hold on for a
second I want you to catch what's going
on here what picture do we see what do
we just read who are the players here
there's the church the woman and she's
about to give birth to who she's about
to give birth to Jesus and who is
standing right before her ready to
devour the child as soon as he's born
Satan here's a question guys think about
this now there's the woman here's the
dragon and he's like as soon as this
child is born I'm going to kill him did
that happen
did he try did it happen no so here's
the question guys how in the world is it
that Satan is standing before this woman
he's watching all this and then the
child escapes who knows what happened in
the actual story what happened right
Jesus is born and then there's a decree
by Herod to do what to kill all the
children under two years old right and I
want you to notice this come with me
notice with me Matthew chapter 2 verse
13 the Bible says here and when they
were departed behold the angel of the
Lord appeared to Joseph in a dream
saying arise take the young child and
his mother and Watts flee into Egypt
so why didn't why didn't Rome find Jesus
because he was what he what he was
hidden he was what he was hidden in fact
the word flee right there in that verse
if you look up in the Strong's
Concordance
one of its meanings is to vanish now we
know that Jesus did not literally
vanished he vanished out of their sight
he was hidden he was not they could not
see him
how many of you rember when Moses was
born the story of Moses born and the
Bible says that what do they do with
Moses because was there a decree to kill
Moses to kill all the male children yeah
but what happened with Moses may I
suggest to you may I suggest to you that
the reason the dragon could not kill
Jesus is because Jesus was invisible
okay I don't know if you caught that
just now guys so let me say it again
may I suggest to you that the woman who
is who was about to give birth and the
dragon is standing right before her
nowhere for Jesus for Jesus to go so I
surely got you may I suggest that the
reason he could not kill the child was
because the child was invisible
how many who catch what I'm saying
the child was invisible in other words
even though he was born in the flesh he
was totally of the spirits and since
spiritual things are spiritually
discerned
Satan could never see Jesus you remember
that time that this crowd surrounded
Jesus and they were like we're gonna
kill you remember that and the Bible
says it says it twice once it's in John
eight the other one is in Luke 4 the
Bible says that Jesus passed through
he's in the crowd and the crowd is like
ha ha we have you now because listen
Satan is flesh seeking and unfortunately
many people are also flesh seeking but
here Jesus is in the midst of them and
the Bible says he passed he passed on
his way so imagine that theory is kilohm
and everyone rushes in Jesus like excuse
me excuse me
excuse me and they're over there
fighting trying to kill him because
Leslie things cannot discern spiritual
things but now there's something I'm
trying to get across to you this morning
and it is that spiritual things are
spiritually discerned
if Christ according to Colossians 1:15
is the image of the invisible God that
means that he himself was invisible
yes visible you could see him you could
see the flesh but in the spiritual world
realm he was invisible and that's why he
couldn't be touched now now please hold
that thought in mind as we look at what
Jesus himself says or wrote through his
prophet in Isaiah 45 verse 2 this is
what he says look unto me and be he
saved all the ends of the earth for I am
God and there is none else so what does
Jesus say what is Jesus calling us to do
look unto Him to be what saved how many
of you want to look unto Him amen but
there's a problem here I don't know if
you know the problem how do you look
unto someone that is invisible
come with me hebrews chapter 11 verse 27
hebrews chapter 11 verse 27 let's see if
we can get up on a screen hebrews
chapter 11 verse 27 listen to what it
says of moses listen to what it says of
moses by the way by the way pause for a
second was moses hidden of god that god
hide moses from the egyptians how long
was moses hidden from the egyptians how
long actually yes but you're talking
about the wrong 40 years how long was
moses hidden from the egyptians since
his birth the egyptians did not know who
moses was or what his mission was so
that god hide moses among the egyptians
but when was he revealed when was he
revealed when the flesh rose up and said
vengeance is mine I'm gonna do that's
when he was exposed so so come back with
me Hebrews 11 verse 27
speaking of Moses the Bible says by
faith he that is Moses forsook Egypt not
fearing the wrath of the King for he
endured as seeing him who is what how
did Moses see him who was invisible
would you like to see him was invisible
how are you gonna see him who is
invisible oh this hebrews chapter 11
verse 1 tell us how to do that oh it
sure does Hebrews 11 verse 1 now faith
is the substance of things hoped for the
evidence of things so how do we see him
who is invisible we see him by what's
safe now now now catch this guys because
I'm going somewhere with this
because the Bible tells us that by
beholding by beholding we become change
into the same image so you understand
what this means right when I behold him
who is invisible man when I behold him
who is invisible who is he that is
invisible Jesus when I behold him who is
invisible
how was he invisible come on someone
tell me how was he invisible because
self was what hidden the flesh was what
hidden see beloved listen this is how
Satan operates Satan was trying to get
Jesus to become visible so how do you do
that spit on him
beat him insult him wait you said what
to me let me show you myself let me
reveal to you who I am
Satan's entire mission was to get Jesus
to show himself just one time because
all I need to do is see you once and
then I have you so check this out guys
if God is trying to tell us look unto me
and be saved what he's trying to tell us
is I need you to look at me because when
you see the unseen you yourself become
unseen
come on let me actually cuz how many of
you are tired of being lured out of
hiding by Satan think about it you know
like it seems sometimes like Satan will
put the right people in your path
specifically to lure you out anybody
have that experience we all know what
it's like I'm gonna love yes sometimes
Satan will use you to lure people out so
don't think it's just like one way or
maniy he learned me I hear sometimes you
can learn people out thank God for being
God for me that I be used to learn
people out from Jesus God forbid that
you be used to learn people out from
Jesus because beloved Satan cares about
one thing only I need to spot the flesh
you see listen how was Jesus invisible
he humbled himself Philippians 2:5 he
humbled himself even unto the death of
the cross Jesus remained invisible
because Jesus
remained submitted so you understand
what this means right if invisible means
submitted then visible means let me tell
you something
Satan is a master of self exaltation
Satan is a master of eye Satan as a
master of you have offended me Satan is
a master of you did this to me Satan is
the master of that and he utilizes that
very thing
I deserve this is mine what are you
doing don't touch he is a master of
using that to bring self out Jesus
humbled himself from stuff that belonged
to him he was God but when they were
like no you're not God he thought it not
robbery to be equal with God and yet he
humbled himself and beloved listen to me
the reason why we have an invisible
church is because there are visible
people inside the church
so God invites us behold him who is
invisible why because the 2nd
Corinthians 4:18 the Bible says this
while we look not at the things which
are seen but at the things which are not
seen for the things which are seen are
temporal but the things which are not
seen are eternal how many of you would
like to be eternal then guess what you
better start looking at the things that
are not seen because by looking at the
things that are seen we are declaring
ourselves to be temporal to be temporary
and beloved yes sometimes Satan will use
us on each other you guys please get
what I'm saying
sometimes Satan will use us on each
other when when deep down yeah you know
what I love you and I love you but
sometimes Satan will get in between
people that actually love each other and
use you to bring out the flesh
remember the story when God says to
Moses they're going through the
wilderness and the people start
murmuring against God and Moses
murmuring against what God is leading
them in and they begin to murmur you're
doing it you you don't know what you're
doing Moses Papa ba ba ba and then God
sends what serpents biting the people by
the people and then what does God say to
Moses when the people start crying on to
him what does God tell him to do I want
you to make a brazen Serpent and put it
on a pole who was that brazen serpent a
symbol of it was a symbol of Christ
check this out guys when the people
stopped looking around and started
looking to the one who is eternal the
Serpent's had no more power over them
now look the Bible doesn't say this but
here's what this is my pastoral
imagination okay if you were looking at
the cross if you were looking at the
serpent on the pole the serpents on the
ground could not find you you see
beloved the secret to invisibility is to
look at the one who himself is invisible
the moment thing can get you to be like
yeah look a brother so-and-so
do you see what brother so-and-so is
doing do you see what sisters own so the
moment he can get us to start playing
that we have taken our eyes off of him
who is invisible and started to look at
they which are visible
Zephaniah to 3cq the Lord all unique of
the earth which have wrought his
judgments seek righteousness seek
meekness it shall be it may be that you
shall be hid in the day of the Lord's
anger let me ask your question how many
of you want to be hidden in the day of
the Lord's anger
that's why Colossians 3:1 says this if
you then be risen with Christ seek those
things which are beneath seek those
things which are on earth seek those
things which are where everyone above
where Christ sitteth on the right hand
of God set your affections on things
above not on things on the earth for you
are what and your life is what hid with
Christ in God beloved if your life is
hidden with Christ in God do not let the
flesh manifest itself because when you
do that your life is no longer hidden in
Christ with God thy word have I hid in
my heart that I might not sin against
thee so if we have the word hiding in
our hearts then we ourselves become
invisible
we ourselves beloved become in visible
jesus said these words John 3 verse 3
jesus answered and said unto them verily
verily I say unto you except a man be
born again he cannot see the kingdom of
God did you catch that just not except a
man be one born again he cannot what why
can't he see the kingdom of God
because he's still in the one in the
flesh and the flesh cannot discern
spiritual things that's why Jesus said
you must be born again but beloved
listen just as Satan stood before the
woman to devour the newborn Jesus so he
stands before you to devour your
born-again experience so if I can
destroy your born-again experience you
can no longer see the kingdom of heaven
and if you can't see the kingdom of
heaven you become purely visible and as
a purely visible person you aren't you
are a dead on target for me but let me
listen to me here is a thing as humans
as those that are that struggle with sin
many of us have such a struggle in our
hearts with the things of the flesh that
if we do not learn to focus on Jesus and
Jesus only if we do not learn to keep
our eyes stayed on cry have you ever
thought to yourself how in the world
one-third of the angels in heaven got
kicked out of the church in heaven you
guys please this is not a joke think
with me how many of you are think you're
better than angels anybody here think
they're better than angels anybody here
think they're wiser than the Angels that
were in heaven before they got kicked
out
how in the world did one third of
intelligent angels how did they get to
the place where God had to say no longer
you're out listen to me beloved sin is a
deadly and dangerous thing and if we
think that we are smart enough to look
at things on the earth and still
maintain our Christianity I don't know
what to tell you I don't know what to
tell you
but I can tell you this when you become
invisible in the church guess what
happens you become visible to the
community I don't know if you thought
ahead we have a problem we are invisible
to the community why because we are
visible in the church so pastor what do
we need to do we need to become
invisible in the church so that we can
become visible to the community because
when we have a church full of
self-sacrificing people a church full of
people who are not concerned about rank
or position or authority or whatever it
is a group of people who say let us all
work together to get the work of God
done when we have that and there's no
battle for position and authority and
beloved listen to me if there's gonna be
a battle for position and authority and
my right versus your right look I listen
guys I did not leave a million dollar
contract I did not leave a position of
fame and authority and all that kind of
stuff to like you know come to a church
I'm not talking about this church but a
church in which P
Oh what Lord should I just like stay
down the industry and witness the people
out there who might be more open and
might be more willing and my sometimes
the most difficult people to to to get
through for God is in his own church
Lord wake us up when I when are we gonna
be tired of the of the inward stuff and
start focusing on the upward stuff st.
job is to lure you out of hiding the
Bible says that what my hiding place
thou shalt preserve me from trouble
they also accomplice me about what songs
of deliverance Psalm 91 he that dwelleth
in the secret place of the Most High
shall abide under the shadow of the
Almighty
so if Christ is our hiding place then no
wonder Satan tries to draw us out
because what is sin man lusts when he is
drawn away of the want from the one who
is trying to draw us to him what does
God want he wants an invisible church he
wants an invisible church but ever
listen to me at the end of time
revelation 6 tells us that there will be
a group of people that when Jesus comes
they will they will run and say hide us
from the face of him that sits on the
throne they will try to become invisible
but it will be too late they try to hide
then because they were not hidden now I
don't want to be in that group I don't
want anyone in this church to be in that
group no one no one beloved please I
plead with you
[Music]
set your affection on things above we
have one mission as seventh-day
adventists and that is not to be higher
or better than some other brother or
sister it is not to cling to what we
think belongs to us or or it is none of
that with a one mission God has given us
is to love one another and to be about
my father's business and beloved if we
can't do that then what are we doing
as a church we can't keep doing Church
as usual if you were Moses you probably
pull your hair out
can you imagine
I'm not Moses thank God but what must
have had I want you to put yourself in
Moses place and God says okay you're
leading the hardest thing to deal with
in Christianity is the people
someone once said church would be fun if
it were not for the people but beloved
unfortunately all of us come broken all
of us please don't think as a pastor and
telling you that you are broken and all
of us come broken but God is able to
take that which is broken and make it
into something beautiful
so
I want an invisible Church God wants an
invisible Church you want an invisible
Church I'm going to invite you to come
come down to the front because we're
going to pray today you're saying Lord
make me invisible make me invisible
whatever it is that Satan has been using
in my life to lead me to be bitter to
leave me to be angry to lead me to
whatever it is lord help me to be
invisible not completing with you Church
let's be invisible
let's be so that when you look at me and
I look at you I don't see you and you
don't see me but we see Jesus how are
you gonna see Jesus in the thief on the
cross
you know what craziness he had done I
can't look at G step thief run across
and see Jesus Jesus said listen that's
not for you to judge
when did we see you and neglect you when
did we see you and and hate you what did
we see you and not feed you when did we
see you and speak mean to you when did
we do this and so much as you did it on
to the least of these my brethren you
did it unto me so if you don't know who
Jesus is brethren is you better be
careful but never listen to me
Christianity is about family boom
bottom line and God says if you can't be
in this family and this is not for you
and family love one another that's the
question is this about family or is it
about self because whatever once it
becomes about family we become that city
set on the hill and beloved that city
set on the hill
you asked what hill it's the hill of
Calvary because that's the hill in which
Jesus demonstrated the greatest
invisibility they spit on him they
mocked him come down you're worthless
you're nothing you've failed and in
spite of all that Jesus remained
invisible